# 你看現在豬 都跑出來了
Look at the pigs! They've come out here.
# 那個籠子沒關住它
The cage couldn't shut them off,
# 那個圍欄
I mean the fence.
# 下來甚麼都吃掉 除了一塊生薑沒吃
They ate up everything once they came down, except a piece of ginger.
# 甚麼都被它們吃光啦
Everything was eaten up.
# 一管啦 讓它們先吃飽了再把它們趕回去
Leave them alone. Let them get stuffed first and then I'll get them back.
# 這母豬都好瘦了
The sow is now really skinny.
# 這它在這
So I let it,
# 外面找好吃的
get some good food here outside.
# 吃根象草
Have an elephant grass!
# 公豬 這個好吃的給你吃
The boar. I leave the good food to you.
# 以前我還經常抱你們兩個 現在那麼大條了
I always snuggled you two before. You are that big now.
# 不敢抱了
I dare not now.
# 這個母豬 母豬好瘦了
The sow, the sow is so skinny now.
# 這它兒子 它兒子都差不多超過你啦 (註︰主語暗換)
It's son. It's son is almost bigger than you now.
# 小狗
Puppy
# 甚麼都吃完啦
Everything has been eat up.
# 那邊有辣椒醬啊 要不要吃點辣椒醬
There is chili sauce. You want some chili sauce?
# 讓它們自由活動一天 是吧 難得出來一趟
Let them be free today, shall we? They don't have much chance to come out.
# 其他還在上面
The rest are still up there,
# 上面一點 (註︰這句不明白)
a bit up there.
# 我上去看一下
Let me go up and have a look.
# 我進去看下 它們從哪裡出來的
Let me go inside and see from where they came out.
# 要把它封起來
I need to block it.
# 不圍起來的話不行
It will be a problem otherwise.
# 哇 全跑啦
Wa! They all run away.
# 有那麼怕我嗎
Are you really that scared of me?
# 哇 好久沒來過這裡啦 你看這橘子黃啦
Wa! I haven't been here for a long time. Look! The tangerines have turned golden yellow.
# 這個是砂糖桔
These are "sugar tangerines".
# 味道還可以哦
It tastes not bad.
# 好甜
Sweet!
# 哇 肚子那麼大
Wa! What a big stomach!
# 那些小豬 好怕我啊
The piglets, are so scared of me.
# 一看到我它就全跑啦
They all run away once they see me.
# 小豬
Piglets!
# 你看
Look!
# 這裡有個洞
Here's a hole.
# 用繩子都沒紥住它
The rope couldn't tie it.
# 把它封起來就好了
Block it, and it's done.
# 等一下把那其他豬放進來
I'll get the other pigs in.
# 再把它
And then,
# 把它封起來就好啦
simply block it.
# 晚上它們會回來的
They'll be coming back at night.
# 這小豬
This piggy...
# 上次你喝醉了我都沒有把你宰了
I didn't kill you when you were drunk last time.
# 還小的時候我抱過你嘞
I have snuggled you when you were still small.
# 你看現在
Look! Now,
# 肥的像頭豬啦 那裡抱得動啊 現在
you're as fat as a pig. How can I snuggle you now?
# 特別是你
Especially you,
# 我頭像都用你的
you are on my profile picture.
# 你還很小的時候
When you were still tiny,
# 鼻子是白的 腳也白的
you had white nose and white feet.